American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIa. 1743-1806 APS.Archives.IIa APS.Archives.IIa
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - G. A. Ebell to [the American Philosophical Society], March 25, 1794; 7 1/2" x 9"; Ebell, G. A.
    Hanover, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French.) Presents his work on the poisonous quality of lead used in glazing. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 223, July 18, 1794.
  - The [American] Philosophical Society to the estate of Jno. W[illia]m Rediger, April 4, 1794; 7 5/8" x 8 1/4"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Tho[ma]s Ruston; receipted by Jno. Chr. Rediger. Receipted bill for £6.12.10 1/2 for services rendered the A.P.S. during 1793-1794.
  - Report of committee appointed to confer with committee of the University [of Pennsylvania] relative to leasing spare rooms in the building of the [American Philosophical] Society, May 30, 1794; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.D.S.: J[oh]n Vaughan.
  - D[avi]d Nassy to the President of the [American] Philosophical Society, May 30, 1794; 7 1/2" x 9"; Nassy, David de Isaac Cohen, 1747-1806
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French.) Offering to contribute toward moving Peale's museum. A.D.S. [2] 15,2p. 2 col.pl. In French. Presented to the Society, Feb. 1794; cf. Minutes of Feb. 21 and March 21,1794. Photo. of plates and t.p. and pp.1-2.
  - Lease issued to Charles Willson Peale for a portion of the Society's hall, July 1, 1794; 9 1/2" x 15"; American Philosophical Society
    D. 3p., end. Counterpart S: C.W.Peale.
  - John Vinall to David Rittenhouse, August 23, 1794; 7 1/4" x 9"; Vinall, John, 1736-1823
    President of the (American) Philosophical Society, Boston, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents a copy of his work (A Systematical Treatise of Arithmetic) to A. P. S. See Pro.XXII, pt. 3, 226, Nov. 7, 1794.
  - Letter to [David] Rittenhouse, Sept. 10, 1794; 12-3/4x8; Fauchet, Joseph, baron, 1761-1834
    Philadelphia, L. 2p.and end. Translation. Sends second part of l'Heritier's work on weights and measures to the APS. Refers to Franklin. See Printed Minutes; pp.225-226 under date of Oct.24, 1794.
  - David Redick to David Rittenhouse, President of A.P.S., September 25, 1794; 7 3/4" x 9"; Redick, David
    Washington, 2 pp., address and endorsement. Presents model of a machine for tempering clay to the A.P.S. See Minutes, November 7, 1794.
  - Tho(ma)s Wright to the Secretary of the (American) Philosophical Society, Nov. 7, 1794; 7 1/2" x 9 3/8"; Wright, Thomas
    Great Ship Street, Dublin, n.d., (read,). 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to A.P.S. "a small work" (A concise history of the human muscles). See Pro. XXII, pt. 3, 226, Nov. 7, 1794.
  - Alexandre Lerebours to [David] Rittenhouse, November 21, 1794; 7 1/4" x 9 3/8"; Lerebours, Alexandre
    President of the (American) Philosophical Society, ----, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French.) Presents to A.P.S. a number of books and pamphlets dealing with useful discoveres and inventions made in France since the commencement of the Revolution. See Pro. XXII, pt. 3, 227,
  - Report of committee upon a paper entitled "A proposed method of working the sails of a ship by mechanic powers,", December 20, 1794; 7 3/16" x 9"; American Philosophical Society
    Philosophical Hall, [Philadelphia], 4 pp. and endorsement. A.D.S.: Jona[than] Williams.
  - Letter to David Rittenhouse, Philadelphia, Aug., 1795; 9x7; Galloway, Joseph, 1731-1803
    L. 2p.and add.,end. Enc. (see Ms. Comm.to the APS. Mechanics, Machinery, Eng., etc., no. 14.) Encloses papers for the premium. For enclosure, see: Americanus. Concerning an improved windlass; [Aug. 1795].
  - Specification of a machine for spinning flax., November, 1795; 7 5/8" x 9 1/8"; Craig, Peter
    --, 1 p. and endorsements. A.Com.S. Received, November 17, 1795; read, November 21, 1795. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 235.
  - Letter to [David Rittenhouse], January 12, 1795; 7 1/2" x 9"; Buchan, David Stewart Erskine, Earl of, 1742-1829
    Dryburgh Abbey, A.L.S. 8p. Presents a writing box dedicated to his use as president of the Philosophical Society. Describes box which contains pictures of Copernicus and Napier. With this letter is a typed copy of an item in the Public Ledger and Daily Transcript, July 9, 1885, about the box. Printed: APS Library Bulletin for 1950, p.292.
  - Letter to M. L'Héritier, Jan. 15, 1795; Rittenhouse, David, 1732-1796
    Photostat of A.Dr. of L.S.: D. Rittenhouse, president of the APS. 1p. (On same sheet is draft of letter from Rittenhouse to M. Fauchet, same date) Acknowledges the receipt of his Stirpes Novae and Monographia Cornus, by the hand of M. Fauchet. Mentions Dr. Franklin. Presented by Princeton university library, from original in possession of Miss Elizabeth Sergeant Abbot, June 1954.
  - Letter to [M. Fauchet], Jan. 15, 1795; Rittenhouse, David, 1732-1796
    Photostat of A.Dr. of L.S. (On same sheet with letter from Rittenhouse to M.L'Héritier) Acknowledges receipt of M. L'Héritier's Stirpes Novae for the APS. Presented by Princeton Univ. Library, June 1954, from original in possession of Miss Elizabeth Sergeant Abbot. of M. Fauchet. Mentions Dr. Franklin. Presented by Princeton university library, from original in possession of Miss Elizabeth Sergeant Abbot, June 1954.
  - Eliphalet Pearson to the Secretary of the [American] Philosophical Society, March 4, 1795; 7 1/2" x 9"; Pearson, Eliphalet, 1752-1826
    Cambridge, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. The American Academy of Arts and Sciences sends its Memoirs, II, pt. 1, to A. P. S. See Pro. XXII, pt. 3, 230, April 17, 1795.
  - Certification that Peter Legaux is a member of the Society, March 13, 1795; 15" x 19"; American Philosophical Society
    D.S: Jn. Vaughan, Peter S. DuPonceau, Benjamin Smith Barton, Andw Ellicott, C.W. Peale, Nicholas Collin, R. Patterson, Dd Nassy. 1p. Notarized by Peter S. DuPonceau, March 14, 1795. Contains his seal.
  - The [American] Philosophical Society to the estate of Tho[ma]s Clifford, March 20, 1795; 6 1/2" x 7 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., [Philadelphia], 2 pp. D.S.: And[re]w Ellicott; receipted by Thomas Clifford and John Clifford. Receipted bill for £14.17.6 for services rendered the A.P.S. during 1771-1772.
  - American Philosophical Society to Jno. Ch[a]r[les] Rediger, March 26, 1795; 7" x 7 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: And[re]w Ellicott. Bill for £2.6.3, for services rendered to the A.P.S. during 1794.
  - The [American] Philosophical Society to Rich[ard] Bache, April 17, 1795; 5 5/8" x 7 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    [Dr., Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S. Rich[ard] Bache. Receipt for £30, being one year's interest on bond due to the late president, Benjamin Franklin.
  - John Vaughan. Memo to Dr. Guenat. A.P.S. subscription list., April 20, 1795; 7 1/2" x 12 5/8"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Treasurer of A.P.S., to John B. Guenat, Dr., [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. D. Receipted by John B. Guenat. Receipted bill for £2.19.3 for collecting £59.05 due to A.P.S. List appended.
  - Johan. Daniel Gros to the Secretary of the (American) Philosophical Society, May 6, 1795; 7 1/2" x 9"; Gros, John Daniel, 1737-1812
    New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Donates to A.P.S. "a moral treatise" on The Natural Principles of Rectitude. See Pro. XXII, pt. 3, 232, May 15, 1795.
  - James Mease to Robert Patterson, May 16, 1795; 7 1/2" x 9"; Mease, James, 1771-1846
    Secretary of the (American) Philosophical Society, Health Office, State Island, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to A.P.S.: (1) West India diseases, 3d. ed., by Dr. Moseley; (2)Coffee, 5th. ed., by Dr. Moseley; (3) Dis
  - Ch[arles] Caldwell to the American Philosophical Society,----, June 1, 1795; 7 7/8" x 9 1/2"; Caldwell, Charles, 1772-1853
    2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S. a translation of J. F. Blumenbach, Physiological Institutes. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 232, June 19, 1795.
  - Concerning improvements in ship pumps, June 19, 1795; 13x8; A.L.O.T.A., pseud.
    [read] D.S.with initials. 8p.and 3 drawings, end. (see Ms.Comm.to the APS. Trade, navigation, etc., no. 16.) Offered for the premium. Enclosed originally in letter from A.L.O.T.A. to Rittenhouse; [read] June 19, 1795. Cf. Minutes, p.232. FILM403 FRAME64
  - Letter to David Rittenhouse, June 19, 1795; 9-1/2x7; A.L.O.T.A., pseud.
    [read] L.S.with initials. 1p. and add., end. Enc. (see Ms.Comm. to the APS. Trade, navigation, etc., no. 16.) Forwards entry for the Magellenic premium. For enc., see: A.L.O.T.A. Concerning... ship pumps; [read] June 19, 1795. FILM403 FRAME 64
  - Letter to the Philosophical society of Philadelphia, June 19, 1795; 7 1/2" x 9"; Nassy, David de Isaac Cohen, 1747-1806
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and add. In French. Expresses appreciation for the honor of being elected to membership. His affairs call him back to Surinam; hope to be useful to the Society from there. Cf. Minutes of June 19, 1795.
  - Heads of a plan for removing the obstructions that the diversity of languages have hitherto thrown in the way of a direct correspondence between the individuals of different natiions. [Philadelphia], n. d., July 17, 1795; 7 3/8" x 9 1/4"; Anderson, James
    read, 44 pp. and endorsement. Com. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 232.
  - J[oh]n Vaughan to the President of the A.P.S., July 17, 1795; 7 3/8" x 8 15/16"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to A.P.S.: (1) John Lorimer's essay on Magnetism; (2) John Lodge Cowley, Illustration and Mensuration of Solid Geometry; and (3) William Jones,
  - Letter to T. Jefferson, Sept. 16, 1795; 8" x 13"; Vautravers, Jean-Rodolphe, b. 1723
    Altona, near Hamburg, A.L.S. 3p. and end. (by Jefferson and others) Donations. Proposed exchange of natural history specimens between A.P.S. and Mr. Patterson, proprietor of the Leverian (?) museum. Mentions Dr. Franklin. Cf. Minutes Aug. 19, 1796.
  - Concerning an improved windlass, Sept. 18, 1795; 13x8; Galloway, Joseph, 1731-1803
    [read], D. 1p.and drawing and end. (see Ms. Comm.to the APS. Mechanics, Machinery, Eng.,etc.,no.14a.) Entered for the premium. Cf. Minutes, p.233. Enclosed originally in letter from Americanus to Rittenhouse;Aug.1795.
  - The American Philosophical Society to Stewart and Cochran, October 16, 1795; 4 3/8" x 7 5/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., ----, 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Nicholas Collin; receipted by Stewart and Cochran. Receipted bill for £4.6.3 for paper and printing of notices during 1794-1795.
  - W[illia]m Jones to John Vaughan, November 3, 1795; 7 1/2" x 9"; Jones, William, 1763-1831
    London, 2 pp. A.L.S. Is constructing a new pair of 18" globes. will be pleased to present a pair to the A.P.S. when finished.
  - Specification of a machine for spinning flax, 1795 November; Craig, Peter
    Specification of a machine for spinning hemp flax.
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, Philadelphia, Nov. 30, 1795; 12-1/2x8; Guest, Henry
    Bruns[wic]k, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Ms.Comm.to the APS. Medicine, anatomy and physiology, no. 6.) Concerning the cure of some diseases. Cf. Minutes, p.235.
  - Letter to W[illiam] Barton, secretary of the American philosophical society, January 26, 1796; 8" x 12 3/4"; Duhail, L. E.
    Norfolk, L.S. 1p. and add. Acknowledges election to membership.
  - Thomas Dobson to the [American] Philosophical Society, February 5, 1796; 7 5/8" x 9 1/8"; Dobson, Thomas, 1751-1823
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Offers terms upon which he will print A.P.S. Transactions, IV.
  - The [American] Philosophical Society to Rich[ard] Bache, February 10, 1796; 6 3/8" x 7 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Dr.], Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Rich[ard] Bache. Receipt for $80, being one year's interest on bond due to the late president, Benjamin Franklin.
  - List of papers in the files of the (American Philosophical) Society, February 13, 1796; 7 7/8" x 13 1/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. D.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., 1796 May 10; Hermann, B.F.J.
    The Russian geologist B.F.J. Hermann wrote to offer two of his latest works to the A.P.S., namely Mineralogical Tours in Siberia; to which is added a Complete history o Minerals of the working mines of that Country. (in German)
  - Letter to the A.P.S., 1796 May 21; Hermann, B.F.J.
    The Russian geologist B.F.J. Hermann wrote to offer two of his latest works to the A.P.S., namely Mineralogical Tours in Siberia; to which is added a Complete history o Minerals of the working mines of that Country. (in English)
  - Report of committee upon the plan of an improvement for a windless, May 12, 1796; 8" x 10 13/16"; American Philosophical Society
    presented by Americanus, Navy Yard, 1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S.: Joshua Humphreys.
  - W[illia]m Bingham to Jno. Vaughan, May 12, 1796; 6 1/4" x 7 7/8"; Bingham, William, 1752-1804
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses a check for $5,000, "which I shall want on the 20th Inst."
  - Letter to D[avid] Rittenhouse, July 3, 1796; 9x7-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and end. (see Ms.Comm. to APS. Natural history, vol. 1, no. 12.) Concerning natural history, fossils.
  - Concerning the telegraph, July 15, 1796; 9x7-1/2; Hill, Henry
    [read] A.D.S. 3p.and end, and 3 illustrations. (see Ms.Comm.to the APS. Mechanics, Machinery, Eng., etc., no.15) Cf. Minutes, p.240.
  - Letter to W[illiam] Barton, July 19, 1796; 8" x 9 1/2"; Cuñat, John Baptiste
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Acknowledges election to membership in the American philosophical society. Cf. Minutes of Sept. 16, 1796.
  - Letter to W[illiam] Barton, July 19, 1796; 8" x 9 1/2"; Jaudenes y Nebot, Joseph de
    Philadelphia A.L.S. 2p. and end. Acknowledges election to membership in the American philosophical society. Encloses letter from Dr. Cañat [July 19, 1796], Cf. Minutes of Sept. 16, 1796.
  - Robert Patterson to Joseph Gatty, August 17, 1796; 6 3/8" x 7 3/8"; Patterson, Robert, 1743-1824
    Dr., ----, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by Joseph Gatty. Receipted bill for £2.5.0 for repairing a wheel barometer.
  - Letter to [Johannes Rodolph Valltravers;], Aug., 1796; 8x6-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    ca. L. 1p. T.Jefferson forwarded his letter but the APS cannot help. For letter, see Valltravers to Jefferson; Sept. 16, 1795.
  - Peter Thomson to William Barton, October 24, 1796; 8" x 9 7/8"; Thomson, Peter
    Sassafras Street, [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Submits for examination and correction the rough draught of a proposed deed from the widow of David Rittenhouse and her daughters to the A.P.S., conveying
  - Royal Society of Valencia to the American Philosophical Society, November 22, 1796; 7 1/2" x 9 1/8"; Sociedad Económica de Amigos del País de Valencia
    Valencia, 3pp. and endorsement. L.S.: Luis de Urbina, Director. (In Spanish.) Informs American Philosophical Society of its collective election to membership in the Royal Society of Valencia. Donates its works. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 255-6, April 21, 1797.
  - Royal Society of Valencia to the American Philosophical Society, November 22, 1796; 8 3/8" x 11 7/8"; Sociedad Económica de Amigos del País de Valencia
    Valencia, 4 pp. Copy. Translation. Informs American Philosophical Society of its collective election to membership in the Royal Society of Valencia. Donates
  - Letter to William Barton, secretary of the A.P.S., November 22, 1796; 8 1/4" x 11 3/4", 8 1/4" x 12"; Urbina, Luis de
    Valencia, L.S. 2p. and end. In Spanish. (Accompanied by translation - 3p.) Acknowledges election to membership and receipt of diploma by Don Joseph de Jaudenes Mentions the R. sociedad economica de amigos del pais de Valencia. Cf. Minutes - April 21, 1797.
  - The Insurance Company of North America to the American Philosophical Society, December 3, 1796; 15" x 18 1/2"; Insurance Company of North America
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsements. D.S.: Cha[rles] Pettit. $4,000 policy on Philosophical Hall.
  - Geo[rge] W. Craik to Sam[uel] Magaw and C[harles] W[illson] Peale, December 12, 1796; 7 15/16" x 9 3/4"; Craik, George W.
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. The President of the United States and his family will attend when an eulogium shall be pronounced to the memory of Dr. David Rittenhouse.
  - Report of the committee upon rules and conditions which have been adopted for the adjudication of the Magellanic premium, December 29, 1796; 7 3/4" x 9 5/16"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Tared Ingersoll, Jona[than] Williams, R[obert] Patterson. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 245.
  - Col. Sergeant to the (American) Philosophical Society,----, 1796; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Sergeant, Col.
    2 pp., address and endorsement. L. Unsigned. Deposits Indian curiosities with the A.P.S. See Minutes, February 19, 1796, in Pro. XXII, pt. 3, 237.
  - Concerning lighthouses and concerning the preservation of meat, 1796; 13x8; Guest, Henry
    D. 3p. (see Ms.Comm.to the APS. Trade, navigation, etc., no. 19.)
  - Letter to the A.P.S., 1796; Guyer, Frederic
    Proposal "to ascertain the Longitude by Lunar observation".
  - On education in public schools, addressed to [Thomas Jefferson], Dec. 30, Jan. 2, 1796, 1797; 7x9-1/2; Hiram,
    A.D.S. 8P. and end. (see Ms.Comm.to APS. Phil.,Lit.,Ant.,Geo., Education, vol. 1, no.6.)
  - Letter to Sam. Magaw, Jonathan Williams, William Barton, and John Bleakly, secretaries of the A.P.S., Jan. 28, 1797; 8" X 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, Copy of L. 3p. and end. Acknowledges election as president of the Society. Printed: A.P.S. Proc.v.22.pt.3, 250; Proc. v.87, no 3, p.267,1943; Trans.v. 4, xii.
  - The [American] Philosophical Society to Rich[ard] Bache, February 12, 1797; 6 3/4" x 7 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
  - W[illiam] Rawle to [Caspar] Wistar, February 23, 1797; 8 1/8" x 9 3/8"; Rawle, William, 1759-1836
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents electrical machine to the A.P.S. See Minutes, February 24, 1797.
  - List of articles presented by George Turner, Feb., 1797; 13-1/4x8-1/4; American Philosophical Society
    D. 2p. See Minutes,Feb.24. 1797,p. 251,for partially printed list.
  - Report of committee upon an anonymous paper on education and public schools, March 10, 1797; 7 15/16" x 12 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 3 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: T[homas] C. James, Rich[ar]d P. Smith, Ch[arles] Caldwell. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 253.
  - [American] Philosophical Society to Tho[ma]s Dobson, March 17, 1797; 7 3/8" x 12"; American Philosophical Society
    [Dr.], Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: C[aspar] Wistar Jun[io]r. Bill for £9.17.5 for stationery.
  - Report of the committee appointed to make an analysis of the second piece on education, March 17, 1797; 7 5/16" x 12 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    submitted for the premium, [Philadelphia], 10 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Jona[than] Williams, Caspar Wistar, Jr., R[obert] Patterson.
  - Remarks on the effects of metallic rocks in the cure of diseases, April 7, 1797; 13x8; Currie, William, 1754-1828
    D.S. 4p.,end. (see Ms.Comm. to the APS. Medicine, anatomy and physiology, no.7.) Cf. Minutes, p.255.
  - Report of the committee appointed to make an analysis of the paper on education, April 15, 1797; 8" x 12 5/8"; American Philosophical Society
    submitted for the premium by "Academicus", [Philadelphia], 3 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Ch[arles] Caldwell, Rich[ar]d P. Smith, Tho[mas] C. James. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 253, 257.
  - Report of the committee appointed to make an analysis of the paper on education, April 17, 1797; 8" x 12 5/8"; American Philosophical Society
    submitted for the premium by "Hiram", [Philadelphia], April 17, 1797. 3 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Ch[arles] Caldwell, Rich[ar]d P. Smith, Tho[mas] C. James. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 253, 257.
  - Report of committee appointed to prepare a catalogue of the books belonging to the [American Philosophical] Society, April 21, 1797; 6" x 8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 255-256.
  - Letter to Dr. Grassi, April 22, 1797; 7 3/4" x 8 1/4"; Barton, William, 1754-1817
    Philadelphia, A.Dr. of L.S. 1p. and end. As secretary of the A.P.S. expresses thanks for " Carte botanique" and an explanatory pamphlet.
  - Report of committee appointed to prepare a catalogue..., May 5, 1797; 7 1/2" x 9"; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Rich. P. Smith, Sam. H. Smith. 3p. and end. See Minutes, May 5, 1797; also Library Bulletin,1943,pp. 76-82.
  - Report of the committee appointed to report on sundry communications relative to stoves and chimneys, May 6, 1797; 8" x 9 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 4 pp. and end endorsement. D.S.: James Woodhouse, Jona[than] Williams. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 254, 257.
  - Report of the committee appointed to revise the bye-laws, May 19, 1797; 7 1/8" x 13 1/4"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. D.S.: Jon[athan] Williams, W[illiam] Barton. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 257.
  - Letter to W[illiam] Barton, secretary, American philosophical society, May 28, 1797; 8" x 9 3/4"; Valentin, Louis, 1758-1829
    Norfolk, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Acknowledges receipt of second copy of his diploma of membership; would have been pleased to have it carry date of original - 1793.
  - The [American] Philosophical Society to John Vaughan, June 2, 1797; 9 1/2" x 15 1/4"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: J[oh]n Vaughan. Accounts and expenditures for the Philosophical Hall from December 31, 1787.
  - Thomas Dobson to John Vaughan, June 2, 1797; 5 1/4" x 8 1/8"; Dobson, Thomas, 1751-1823
    Treasurer of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S.: Thomas Dobson. Receipt for £9.17.5 paid by A.P.S. for stationery.
  - List of books presented by the Chev., June 6, 1797; 8" x 11"; American Philosophical Society
    Cypriano Rebeiro Freire, D. 2p.
  - Report of the committee appointed to draw up rules and regulations for a standing committee for collecting information as to the antiquities of North America, June 16, 1797; 7 3/4" x 12 3/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia,] 2 pp. Dr.D. Incomplete. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 258, 260, 261.
  - [American] Philosophical Society to W[illia]m Y. Birch, June 21, 1797; 4" x 8 1/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Dr.], Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: James Woodhouse; receipted by Will[ia]m Y. Birch. Receipted bill for $6.00, for quire of large drawing paper.
  - [American] Philosophical Society to James Thackara, June 27, 1797; 3 7/8" x 8 3/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: James Woodhouse; receipted by Daniel Dent. Receipted bill for £15 for printing 95 certificates.
  - Letter to [I. Caffrey;], June, 1797; 9x7; American Philosophical Society
    ca. L. 9p.and end. (see Ms. comm. to the APS. Natural history, vol. 2, no. 87.) Concerning the wish to acquire a complete skeleton of a mammoth. Cf. Minutes, p.258.
  - Letter to W[illiam] Barton, Secretary, American philosophical society, July 1, 1797; 8" x 9 3/4"; Van Braam Houckgeest, André Everard, 1739-1801
    China's Retreat, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Acknowledges election to membership.
  - Report of the committee on Couldery's lamp, July 21, 1797; 7 1/2" x 9 1/16"; American Philosophical Society